If I one day become a mere bandit,
I ask that you strike me down.
I ask that you do the same,
if I begin walking a similar path.
A sickness, in her blood?
There is currently no cure for such illness.
We shall organize the Zhisi Squadron.
I am Wang Lun, the leader of Liangshan Marsh.
Does our imperial court now
warrant such fighting?
Defect, and you will find your path!
You have proven your incompetence.
Prove yourself useful in the Qingzhou army.
Is he a dog of the Imperial Guard?
To Lin Chong's victory. Cheers!
Cheers!
Lin Chong!
[Liangshan Marsh]
Is Lin Chong...
He was poisoned.
Drinks were served using jade cups.
If they drank from silver,
the mark of poison would remain.
Our opponent is no amateur.
Who would do such a thing?
No, I am innocent, An Dao Quan!
I am a doctor.
The culprit is of no interest to me.
I only care about saving my patients.
Leave us. We cannot entertain visitors.
Right.
I apologize for intruding.
Watch yourself. He saw you enter.
A measure against poisoning?
Yes. Prepare any antidotes ahead of time.
The more, the better.
Will that be possible, Xue Yong?
Yes, however...
Speak.
Some poisons kill instantly,
leaving no time for antidotes.
Which is why I have brought along
the best apothecary in the land.
What measures can be taken?
There is one way to circumvent such poisons.
How?
You must take the antidote ahead of time,
to buy time until proper treatment.
Then take it I shall.
Yet why only worry about poison?
There are many other ways to kill a man.
Only poison could kill a man like myself.
For I am strong.
Show me that strength of yours, Lin Chong.
What a wound.
[Episode 5]
Poor fellow.
He was mauled by a tiger.
Is there truly a man-eating tiger
around these parts?
Care to linger, and find out?
Really, what a shame for him.
Another young one, gone and killed.
Surely he could have died elsewhere.
I have slain the tiger.
Pardon? You slayed the tiger?
I beat it to death.
D-Do not lie, lad.
A mere human could never best a mighty tiger!
If only...
I were lying.
- Sir, it's terrible!
- Wh-What now?
A massive tiger lies dead
in the clearing ahead!
- The tiger is dead?
- Impossible.
Hello?
Is there anyone home?
Po Xi?
Sir Song Jiang.
Is it true,
Chen Li's condition has taken a turn?
Yes. She is currently resting
after taking some medicine.
I see.
Will she...
We can only help to ease her pain.
Zhu Gui has not left her side in days.
Is that so.
I bring flowers,
to lift the patient's spirits.
Thank you, sir.
Xue Yong.
I hear Lin Chong is recovering well?
Yes. It is a blessing he drank an antidote
ahead of time.
I cannot continue to send him
on these dangerous missions...
Do not be glum, Song Jiang.
Else you will collapse next.
My struggle is nothing, compared to you all.
Xue Yong.
Would you pass this to Lin Chong?
It details various reports
from across the land.
Of course.
Shall I pass a message to him as well?
A message, you say...
Chen Li!
The medicine, please.
Medicine will help her no further.
Chen Li!
Chen Li...
What is it?
Try again, please.
Chen Li?
What did you say, Chen Li?
Chen Li!
"Thank you".
I believe that is what she mouthed to you.
Sir Song Jiang.
Thank you.
Thank you for giving my wife and I
the time to speak again.
You allowed us to make up for lost time.
She and I... We spoke all that we could.
Dr. An Dao Quan.
Dr. Xue Yong.
Thank you.
Yan Po Xi, thank you.
Ruan Xiao Wu, thank you.
Chen Li...
- Chen Li...
- Let us give them space.
Please ask Lin Chong one question.
Lin Chong.
I see you are well.
What a blessing to us all.
Here. I have brought you a gift.
Thank you kindly, sir.
We have executed your assailant.
I apologize for the trouble he caused.
I am relieved to hear he is gone.
Sir, my patient has yet to fully recover.
Right. I apologize for intruding.
He is sitting over there.
But the poor lad won't speak a word.
Could you allow us some time alone?
Of course.
The hero who slayed a tiger
with his bare hands, is it?
I cannot believe I'm greeted
with a familiar face.
Wu Song.
I should have expected as such.
[Wu Song, Tiger-slaying Hero (Ally)]
I am glad to see you well.
You look gaunt, my friend.
Were you gravely injured?
Speak to me, Wu Song.
What happened to you?
The tiger-slaying hero,
reduced to a mere husk.
Was your heart wounded in the fight?
Reminds me of those fists of yours.
You require a doctor.
Only one man in this land
could heal your soul.
I am certain he will save you.
Yang Zhi is displeased
with the current state of this nation.
He is a descendant
of a Song Dynasty hero, after all.
Can we appeal to his frustration,
and bring him to our side?
Unfortunately, his strong beliefs
are also his biggest obstacle.
As a descendant of a hero,
he feels he cannot betray the nation.
Bloodlines, for better or for worse,
tend to shackle us.
Gongsun Sheng is correct.
To which I raise a plan.
We will have the nation
cast Yang Zhi aside.
How so?
Yang Zhi has been ordered
to deliver Cai Jing his bribes.
We will have our men steal his cargo.
Meaning Yang Zhi will fail his mission.
Our opponent is a cautious warrior.
This will be no easy task.
We must plan our next moves carefully.
Gongsun Sheng.
[Gongsun Sheng, Zhisi Squadron]
Are you off to visit Lin Chong, again?
Yes.
Did my first warning not suffice?
Du Qian, has greed taken your soul as well?
It would never.
But you are only drawing
Wang Lun's suspicion.
And you fear his suspect gaze?
I fear the discord it could cause.
Wang Lun is now a beast
who knows no trust.
Then what does that make us,
the protectors of said beast?
I crave meat. Even sheep will do.
Quiet. Eat your meal.
Excuse me, gentlemen.
I bring food,
to celebrate your appetite's recovery.
Here, eat.
You do not need to prove the food is safe.
I never suspected you, Song Wan.
Wang Lun has an army of 300 men
under his direct command.
He calls this army of his,
his Imperial Guard.
Imperial Guard?
Yes.
He has come to believe
he is an emperor of sorts.
I question where his old ambitions have gone.
Yet we only turned
a blind eye to this change.
I am his second-in-command.
Song Wan, his third.
We have seen the men
who spoke against Wang Lun.
The ones who were jailed,
and ultimately assassinated.
Why are you sharing your stories with me?
Your arrival here shook my core.
You survived the Imperial Guard's prison.
You then escaped another soon after.
And now, you have infiltrated
this perilous fortress.
You fear no cell,
nor assassin which may come your way.
Yet my admiration for you
may prove to be my demise.
For I am a weak man.
You are not weak.
When I witnessed your poisoning,
I came to despise myself.
I had only learned to cower
in Wang Lun's presence.
That is why...
Taking Wang Lun's neck
is a rather simple task.
Yet if we kill him now,
it will only cause conflict.
That is why we first require a new leader.
Please wait for his arrival a moment longer.
You will not take the mantle yourself?
[Enforcing the Way in Heaven's Name]
When we are ready, I will wear a black obi.
Until then, await my signal.
[Beijing]
The descendant of a hero, escorting bribes?
How utterly humiliating.
I will have you both join Yang Zhi's troop.
What a pity, indeed.
[Kong Ming, Qingzhou Army (Ally)]
First demoted,
and now transporting "cargo" for Cai Jing.
He remains unaware of what he carries.
[Kong Liang, Qingzhou Army (Ally)]
Bai Sheng.
Good evening, sirs.
- Who is this?
- A thief.
A man fit for the job.
You will find his skills useful.
So we steal the loot,
without hurting Yang Zhi, eh?
Certainly you must be dreaming.
Bai Sheng, was it?
You dare disrespect the trust
Chao Gai and Wu Yong have in you?
They don't trust me.
Chao Gai has chosen this man for the job.
We share a common goal.
What goals?
I couldn't care less about 'em.
Run your mouth all you wish.
The graveyard is full of boasting men
who all died in vain like yourself.
You think I fear death?
Look at this scar.
What about it?
I had my rotting stomach
taken out in the snow.
I died once already when it happened.
In the snow?
You must be the man who escaped
with An Dao Quan and Lin Chong.
If not for them, I'd be a dead man.
I want to join my saviors in that fortress.
Which means I need to gain trust, first.
Every man here has their own motives.
Yet we each aim for the same end point.
Is that not enough for you all?
I apologize for offending you, Bai Sheng.
Let us execute this operation, together.
It will feel great to steal a man's bribe.
I count on your expertise to aid us.
When will the operation commence?
In seven days' time.
Wu Yong has expertly plotted a plan for us.
Yan Qing.
[Mount Ziniu]
We will arrive shortly.
You holding up alright?
Wu Song.
Does it not feel nice
to simply walk an isolated mountain path?
I wonder, is that a shrike?
Do not worry. You will learn to speak again.
Look there.
We have just about arrived.
What a calming place this is.
Indeed. I find the solitude quite relaxing.
[Wang Jin, Former Martial Arts Instructor]
Lu Zhi Shen.
My martial arts is incapable
of reforming this world.
Then I shall not pester any further.
But if I may ask, why not?
My teachings require much self-reflecting.
Then while it may not reform the world,
perhaps it may help reform a lost soul.
How about it?
Your letter was concise enough.
I know what you ask of me.
Is he the one you call Wu Song?
Yes. He is practically a dead man walking.
I understand.
I shall watch over him here.
Wu Song.
Ground yourself by touching this soil.
Your wounds will heal in due time.
That is what you must believe.
Believe, and wake up to a new day.
That is all I ask of you.
And you will repeat this cycle,
for as long as you need to.
Rest easy.
Life here will change you.
Lu Zhi Shen.
Where will your journey take you next?
I plan to travel down south.
I see.
May I entrust you with a letter for Shi Jin?
A letter?
I worry he will have lost his way,
and addressed my concerns in writing.
Wait a moment, I will bring it here.
Please, quench yourself
after your long journey.
Lu Zhi Shen.
Why are his fists so battered?
He trained by pummeling tree and rock.
I believe he felt pain
was a necessity to him.
My, what a poor soul.
Your fists are filled with sadness.
This is...
Those are winter daphnes.
We use them for antidotes.
I see.
Do you like winter daphnes?
No.
I do not.
I hear we established
our own Zhisi Squadron.
A covert squad will prove useful.
How are things on your end?
Wang Lun has rotted to the core.
Yet we cannot underestimate
the power he has built within this fortress.
Though many secretly despise Wang Lun,
they can only cower at his glare.
All who rebel against Wang Lun are killed,
or imprisoned in the dark,
until they've gone mad.
Rebel!
It is difficult to garner support
from those who obey out of fear.
I see.
Your porridge.
I must continue to gather allies
within these walls.
Please tell Chao Gai
we are not yet ready for his attack.
Of course.
- Thank you.
- No problem.
Before I forget, Song Jiang
had a rather strange question for you.
What is it?
Well...
He simply asked about the name of your wife.
My wife?
Yes.
My wife's name...
I no longer remember it.
That is my answer to him.
Are you certain?
This porridge is delicious.
It is filled with spring greens,
all of which have medicinal effects.
I envy your natural skill
to concoct medicines.
I only excel at killing my fellow men.
[Chancellor's Cargo]
Why use such a blade for the Imperial Guard,
and not for our people?
[Yang Zhi, Qingzhou Army Officer]
Yang Zhi.
I am honored to have you at my abode.
May I offer a drink?
No, I will refrain.
I am currently on duty.
I apologize for declining such generosity.
Yang Zhi, have you forgotten what day it is?
Pardon?
It is the day the hero, Yang Ye, passed.
What is this?
This is the very cup Yang Ye once used.
So you say...
What went through his mind,
as he drank his liquor? I do wonder.
If I have begun to question my orders,
what do you reckon I should do, Lu Jun Yi?
Soldiers are not meant to question orders.
And yet, if I still do?
Then you must quit,
and be a soldier no longer.
Else you'd quit being a human altogether.
Tonight, let us raise a toast
to your ancestors,
as a sort of offering to them.
Yan Qing.
Yang Zhi.
A commander must not drink in solitude.
Why not extend this celebration
to your men as well?
Indeed.
I have a message for our men.
Tell them they may enjoy a drink tonight.
Yes, sir.
The commander is letting us drink!
My, my.
It seems one drink will not suffice.
That, it won't.
Please, go on.
Mount Huangni...
Yes, it will surely be a difficult climb
after the liquor Lu Jun Yi has offered them.
Liquor will only fuel
the frustration in these soldiers.
This is where Kong Ming
and Kong Liang will shine.
Treat the cargo with care!
[Mount Huangni]
- Your response?
- Yes, sir!
We will take our mountain climb slow.
Else we'd lack the strength
to whisk the cargo away.
Wu Yong, finish the explanation.
By the time they reach the peak,
Yang Zhi's hungover men will be exhausted.
March!
These are grueling slopes, sir.
Our men are clearly faltering.
They had too much to drink last night.
Push on!
This is where Kong Liang
will suggest taking a break.
Sir, we must let our men rest.
Right.
We'll be taking a break here.
- Hurry.
- Just a bit further.
Sirs.
There, the Ruan brothers, Bai Sheng,
and Gongsun Sheng
will act as water peddlers.
Like an oasis found in a desert.
Will this be enough to slow Yang Zhi's march?
That is where our other trick comes in play.
There has been a bandit attack up ahead.
Understood.
What now?
Bandits, sir.
It seems hundreds
are assailing a village up ahead.
These peddlers are stuck here
in fear of the crossfire.
The local clerks are of course no help.
Can't they do more?
Quiet!
Sir, please forgive my insolence.
Ignore us peddlers.
I realize you have far more
important business to attend to.
Yang Zhi, with his strong sense of justice,
will have his hero's heart
set ablaze by such a statement.
Kong Ming and Kong Liang
will then give him one last push.
We are currently escorting cargo
to Chancellor Cai Jing.
We have no orders to vanquish any bandits.
Orders are orders. What a shame.
No. Our citizens are in need.
We must lend them a hand.
Bandits are but a disorderly gathering.
It will not take long to do away with them.
Kong Liang.
Take half our men as a vanguard.
We must chase away these terrorizing bandits.
If possible, bring me the ringleader as well.
Come this far,
and our victory is guaranteed.
Yang Zhi, I must make one request.
Our men will require sustenance.
You there. I'd like my men to have water.
Will this suffice?
S-Such generosity!
Please, drink everything we have.
- Go on.
- Get your water.
Here, please.
- Thank you so much.
- Hurry.
Here.
Please, take as much as you need.
Are we replenished?
Then we ride on.
Drink, drink.
The village is up ahead.
That way.
Here, drink. Drink.
Any more?
For you, sir.
A paralysis poison.
We hold no ill will towards you, Yang Zhi.
Cai Jing is simply not worthy of this cargo.
What?
You will not die.
We were ordered to keep you alive.
Yang Zhi,
you were transporting bribes
meant for Chancellor Cai Jing.
They have deceived the descendant of a hero
to unknowingly dirty his own hands.
Do you still defend
this utterly corrupt nation?
We await you at Liangshan Marsh.
Chancellor Cai Jing was angered.
That is quite rare for the chancellor.
It cannot be helped.
A meager troupe of bandits
robbed the illustrious Qingzhou army.
Yet they committed theft
without harming any of Yang Zhi's men.
We must be against quite the tactician.
They are far too crafty for mere bandits.
I am especially suspicious of one individual.
A man named Chao Gai, of Yuncheng.
Let me hear your reasoning.
Lin Chong's escort was ambushed by bandits.
Two soldiers came out of the attack alive,
and successfully escorted him to prison.
We were ambushed by bandits.
We do not know their intentions.
Bring him here.
I figured it would not hurt
to torture the escort.
Only two nails were lost,
and the man began blabbering.
He says it was part of a plan
to free the doctor, An Dao Quan.
The one spearheading this operation
was a man named Chao Gai.
Yet that is not all.
Go on.
This Chao Gai was dressed
as the Pagoda-Shifting Heavenly King.
The two men are one and the same.
Was he accompanied by a large, bald monk?
I see.
And his name?
His name!
What was that?
Lu Zhi Shen.
Lu Zhi Shen?
The one who saved Gongsun Sheng
was the Pagoda-Shifting Heavenly King.
Lin Chong has escaped to Liangshan Marsh.
Are all these points connected?
This is no laughing matter.
How shall we combat this?
I will make a report to Cai Jing.
And what will you propose?
That we deploy 4,000 of our soldiers
from Beijing.
Li Fu.
Yes, sir.
I will capture Chao Gai at once.
No.
Kill him.
Fire transforms into a plethora of shapes.
No flame is the same
as any that come before it.
My job is to simply stoke the flame...
by feeding it the branches it needs to grow.
Song Jiang and I both.
Funnily enough, when I first met Song Jiang,
I made a similar remark
about becoming a branch for him.
When starting a fire,
one must first collect the branches.
I shall become one of your many branches.
I apologize for being late.
What else have we learned from the fortress?
Wang Lun is cautious,
and always accompanied by a guard.
Though several wish to join our cause,
they fear Wang Lun,
and cannot act out against him.
To change the hearts of those ruled by fear,
we need some other catalyst.
I see.
Then it will be impossible
to recruit Wang Lun after all...
Where have we placed the stolen cargo?
Right over there.
Trouble!
We have trouble, sir!
What is it?
4,000 soldiers
have been deployed from Beijing.
They aim...
For your neck, Chao Gai.
What?
[Chao Gai]
- Do you know this man?
- No.
Have you seen this man?
Do you know this man?
[Yuncheng]
He is not an easy man to find.
- Wang He.
- Yes, sir?
Gather our spies.
Search every place a bug like him
may scuttle under.
The Chancellor has graced us with extra men.
We may as well put them to use.
Yes, sir.
Wait.
- I have him.
- Pardon?
If I were Chao Gai,
there is only one place to escape to.
Chao Gai, that is a foolish move.
I will simply bargain my way
into Liangshan Marsh.
You will follow Lin Chong into those walls?
This is a job only I can fulfill.
- You will be killed.
- No.
Chao Gai is a chivalrous bandit,
who stole from a chancellor.
Wang Lun will not easily turn away
such a like-minded individual.
He tried to assassinate Lin Chong.
He is clearly far gone.
If he truly wished to conquer the heavens,
then he would keep his warriors.
Yet he attempted to kill
one of his best soldiers.
He is merely a man obsessed with power.
You will be killed, Chao Gai!
Though it is a gamble,
it is one I am willing to take.
I will head straight for that fortress.
Song Jiang.
I ask that you trust me.
You must leave this place immediately.
Why?
The Beijing troops will stay
at your abode in Yuncheng.
They cannot know you wrote
"Enforcing the Way in Heaven's Name".
Your name is not yet associated with us.
This will prove useful to us in the future.
Lin Chong led his life in isolation.
Lu Zhi Shen spreads my word
to those across the nation.
And now, you are heading into Death's maw.
Yet I alone remain safe?
Must I sit, and wait for my reports?
I am left to my own wits,
dreaming my dreams in solitude.
That is your fight to fight.
It is a battle...
far more grueling than mine.
- Load the ship.
- Yes, sir.
The fortress at Liangshan Marsh?
Will Wang Lun become ally to Chao Gai?
A bandit who stole from a chancellor
is being chased by 4,000 soldiers.
Though it is a gamble,
there is nowhere else he can run.
Hurry, and ready our men.
We must catch him before he makes his escape.
Yes, sir.
Chao Gai!
Song Jiang.
I told you, you mustn't come.
I brought you liquor,
to keep you warm on the waters.
Let us share a cup, as we part ways.
I thought you chose not to drink.
I will make an exception.
- Shall I?
- Thank you.
Let us depart while the Zhisi Squadron
distract the pursuing soldiers.
We run short on time.
Song Jiang.
Think of yourself this way.
You are the moon,
hidden by the afternoon sun.
You bring no attention to yourself now.
I understand the pain that must bring.
But the moon will one day
illuminate these dark times.
We all are comrades, united by one cause.
We all know you are suffering most of all.
Chao Gai...
Your drinks.
Thank you.
To our future abode.
I shall see you soon, my friend.
Chao Gai.
I have received your message.
Loud and clear.
Clear a path for our future!
[Enforcing the Way in Heaven's Name]
Lin Chong!
The bells are sounding.
Two boats are headed for our fortress.
What?
4,000 soldiers?
Yes, sir. They are stationed
at the edges of the marsh.
We believe they are with the Beijing army.
There are also two unidentified boats
headed our way.
What is going on?
Increase the guard on our shores.
Yes, sir.
I believe the Pagoda-Shifting Heavenly King
rides that boat.
He is my comrade.
What?
Was this not a fortress of the heart?
You've exposed yourself, Lin Chong!
The citizens' voices shall become our orders.
Yang Zhi, the Blue-faced beast.
I will make a country here.
I will call this country, Mount Liang.
A third-rate spy will always leave a trail.
What about Wang Jin enamored you?
Was it merely his strength?
I made love to Deng Li Hua.
They have established a perch for themselves.
No, not yet.
The author of "Enforcing the Way
in Heaven's Name" still remains at large.
By raising the price of our salt,
we have cornered Chao Gai's foe.
Qinglian Temple...
[Episode 5 - FIN]